

Roberto Zen

Born: 24 November, 1992

Address: Via Nardi 12, Romano d'Ezzelino (VI, Italy)

Phone: +39 347 5645336

E-mail: roberto.zen@outlook.com

22 years old, master student in Computer Science. I am looking for opportunities that allow me to learn and have fun while learning. During the week I am a student and a worker while in the weekend I do private lessons in Math and Computer Science for junior high school and high school students. I do jogging twice a week and I've played baseball for 8 years. I attended many events as volunteer. I am glad to help people whether I can.

Education:

July 2014 Bachelor Degree in Computer Science at University of Trento (TN, Italy).

Mark 108/110.

Algorithms and Data Structures, Software Engineering, Database systems, Theoretical foundations of CS, Computer Networks, Functional programming, Mathematics,

Computer architectures and Operating systems.

Thesis: Gherkin* and Cucumber*: a new approach to testing Ruby on Rails web applications.

Supervisors: Prof. Marchese Maurizio and Prof. Villafiorita Adolfo.

2006 - 2011 Computer Science technician.

Final mark: 90/100.

I.T.I.S. E. Fermi High School, Bassano del Grappa (VI, Italy).

Theoretical foundations of CS, Computer architectures, Operating systems, Mathe-

matics, Probability and Statistics, Electronics and Telecommunications.

Working Experience:

Jan 2012 - now Web developer and tester.

Fondazione Bruno Kessler (ICT4G Research Unit) [http://www.fbk.eu] After 3 months of internship I became a tester for Ruby on Rals web applications. I use Cucumber, RSpec and Capybara Ruby gems to test BringTheFood, a crowd-sourcing web and mobile application that allows people to fight food waste. We use the Scrum methodology and we keep track of our development

process with Redmine.

03/2012 - 10/2013 150 hours collaborator at University of Trento.

Administrative tasks in the structure of the University of Trento. Activities in the IT structures and basic front-office services. Connection and preparation of the classrooms. Lectures Streaming. Student assistance: connection, login and other general problems.

02/07/2012 - 31/08/2012 $\,$ Worker at F.LLI CAMPAGNOLO S.P.A.

02/08/2010 - 20/08/2010 Clothes packaging.

11/08/2009 - 11/09/2009

18/07/2011 - 18/08/2011 Software developer at KREATIVA S.R.L.

Design and development of a Windows Form application used for the

management of musical events.

24/05/2010 - 30/07/2010 Software developer intern at TIELOGIC

Development of Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) applications used for the remote control of machines for gold chain manufac-

turing.

I used Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) with Ms. Visual

Studio 10 and Ms. Expression Blend.

Research Interests:

My fields of interest are Software engineering methodologies with a particular focus on Software testing: Test Driven Development (TDD) and Behavior Driven Development (BDD). Formal verification, formal languages and compilers.

Languages:

Italian: mother tongue.

English: obtained Toefl iBT on march 2014 with a mark of 64/120.

I authorise the use of my personal data in compliance with Legislative Decree 196/03.